teacherweb.com 2016-06-29

# TeacherWeb® Privacy Policy

**NOTICE TO USERS/SUBSCRIBERS:**

**PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING INFORMATION CAREFULLY BEFORE CREATING, USING, OR ACCESSING A TEACHERWEB® SITE. ANY USE OF THE TEACHERWEB® SERVICE, INCLUDING THE CREATION, USE, OR ACCESS OF ANY TEACHERWEB® SITE OR ANY OTHER SERVICES PROVIDED BY TEACHERWEB, WILL SIGNIFY THAT YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS (THE “AGREEMENT”), WHICH INCLUDES TEACHERWEB’S SECURITY AND PRIVACY POLICIES, AND WILL CONFIRM YOUR UNCONDITIONAL CONSENT TO BE BOUND BY THE AGREEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE POSTED AGREEMENT, YOU SHOULD NOT CREATE OR USE A TEACHERWEB® SITE, OR OTHERWISE USE THE SERVICE. TEACHERWEB RESERVES THE RIGHT TO MODIFY THE AGREEMENT IN ITS SOLE DISCRETION AT ANY TIME. PLEASE BE ADVISED THAT TEACHERWEB® IS A REGISTERED TRADEMARK OF TEACHERWEB, INC.**

#### TeacherWeb® Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was developed to give you a full understanding of the terms and conditions relating to information collected through your TeacherWeb® website and TeacherWeb® school website. This information also pertains to TeacherWebQuest and any academic use of TeacherWeb site functionality.

This Privacy Policy pertains only to the information that TeacherWeb® collects or that is provided to us by you and/or your organization. Your organization may have its own policies addressing collection, use and sharing of personally identifiable information. For information about your organization's policy, please contact your organization directly. 

##### I.Registration; Information We Collect

You may visit TeacherWeb® sites as a guest without registering. Teachers and other school personnel will be required to register to update and maintain TeacherWeb sites. Registration, however, will give you access to certain features as well as the ability to personalize certain features which are not available to non-registrants. 

###### A. Personally Identifiable Information

TeacherWeb collects personal information via registration and through features of TeacherWeb® as explained below. 

  1. **Registration occurs in the following ways:**
    1. **Self-Registration.** You may register for a TeacherWeb® site if you meet the criteria outlined in our Terms and Conditions. At the time of registration, we will collect personally identifiable information. 
    2. **School-Registration (i.e. “Pre-Registration”).** Your school may register for a TeacherWeb® site on your behalf, including setting up the site and inputting your personally identifiable information. 
    3. **TeacherWeb Assisted Registration:** TeacherWeb may create a site on your behalf using information that you or your school provides. 
    4. **TeacherWeb user partial registration:** A TeacherWeb® user may input information that can be used to track the end user through features such as alternate passwords, protected pages, newsflash mailing lists, grades features, and other features as not yet introduced. 
    5. **Information collected through features:**
      1. TeacherWeb may collect information about end users through various features of our site. This could include names and email addresses as well as other information that is put onto a site.
      2. TeacherWeb may collect names, ages, and pictures as have been posted on TeacherWeb sites by registered users.
      3. TeacherWeb may collect original posted images and may alter the images (including resizing and optimizing) to adjust them from their original form.
      4. Support Requests may contain personally identifiable information. This information is collected to serve you more effectively and efficiently.
      5. At TeacherWeb we integrate external features into our service (for example Google’s Safe Search feature). The companies that support these external features may collect additional information and are governed by separate policies.
  2. **Details of Self-Registration.**

If you choose to become a registered guest, we will ask for personal information from you through your organization's site powered by TeacherWeb. After we collect this information from you, it may be verified by an official at your organization. Children under 13 years of age are not allowed to register themselves with your organization's TeacherWeb site or the MyTeacherWeb.com service. Before a child under 13 may access features that require registration, the organization must first obtain a signed parental consent form or the student must confirm that they have parental permission to register. If you have questions regarding your profile, please contact your organization's Primary Contact to TeacherWeb.

    1. If you are over 13 years of age, you are required to supply your First and Last Name, Email Address, Sign-In Name and Password and other required fields to use personalization features of TeacherWeb®, including MyTeacherWeb.com. 
  3. **Pre-Registration.**

You may be pre-registered by your organization in one of two ways. Either way, your organization may not share personal information of, about or for children under 13 years of age with TeacherWeb without first receiving parental consent.

    1. Your registration information may be shared with TeacherWeb via a school-provided list. TeacherWeb would use this list to conduct a batch import of information. 
    2. A school-designated individual may input registration information for you. 
    3. Schools are ultimately responsible for any Content posted by the Content Administrator or TeacherWeb Subscriber related to individual students and should have their own approvals to post the Content on the Site.
  4. **Other Information That May Be Collected.**

When visiting the TeacherWeb corporate site at [www.TeacherWeb.com](http://www.teacherweb.com/), personally identifiable information is collected in several ways. For example, we may ask for contact information when you correspond with us, request a demonstration, register for a seminar, inquire about special offers or programs, etc. Depending on the nature of your submission of personally identifiable information, a TeacherWeb representative may contact you to gather or share additional information. No personally identifiable information will be shared with third parties directly by TeacherWeb. Content added to a TeacherWeb® site (for example widgets) may collect information. The information collected is solely governed by the Widget and use of the information is bound by the policies of the Widget. 

  5. **Uses of Collected Information.**

Information collected for registration may also be used to: 

    1. provide you with important information about your school's site, such as updates or notices,
    2. improve our product and services, 
    3. improve customer service and/or 
    4. in aggregate, guide our internal marketing efforts. 
    5. Communicate to you information about other TeacherWeb services or offers from TeacherWeb® chosen third party organizations.

No personally identifiable information will be shared with third parties for general purposes. However, such information may be used for marketing or survey purposes that TeacherWeb decides that involve third party organizations.

It is important to understand that sites powered by TeacherWeb are used to present and archive information supplied by content contributors designated by your organization. TeacherWeb does not supply the organization and classroom specific content appearing on any TeacherWeb sites. 

Once posted to a TeacherWeb® site, content supplied by content contributors at your organization is public information available via the Internet.

##### II.Privacy of Children

TeacherWeb is dedicated to the privacy of children under 13 years of age. We do not collect or entice (by use of contests, games, prizes, or other enticements) from children more information than is needed to access services. We will not share any personal information about children with third parties.

Subscribers and Content Administrators are responsible for all content placed on a site. Subscribers and Content Administrators are responsible for all appropriate parental consent forms, particularly for children under 13 as is required to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). Parents should contact the site Subscriber and Content Administrator to request any information related to their student be removed from a site.

##### III.How We Use Information

  1. **Profile**

We do not associate information that we collect through log files or third parties with your personal profile. The information is provided voluntarily by you when you register for the site. A profile is stored information that gives you access to certain features as well as the ability to personalize certain features. Your profile can be used only by you, TeacherWeb and your organization.

  2. **Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on your computer tied to information about you. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply.

TeacherWeb uses session or dynamic cookies to let us know when a user is signed in or using certain features of TeacherWeb®. Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates or cookies terminate within an allotted period of time. All cookies that persist will only contain information supplied by yourself or that you looked at on a TeacherWeb® site.

When a user is signed in to the service and depending on the user's assigned role(s), additional services may become available through our menu system. Again, depending on your assigned role(s), cookies may offer the following benefits after Sign-In:

    1. A personalized salutation greeting 
    2. Content tailored to your role(s)
    3. Use of services that require Sign-In 
    4. Session time-out, a security feature 

You can disable cookies in your browser's preferences. If you disable cookies in your browser, you may still use your TeacherWeb® site. Services, however, that require Sign-In will not work if cookies are disabled and some Services that require cookies to browse information (or comment on information) will not work.

TeacherWeb may use third party statistic tracking and advertising solicitation cookies. These cookies may persist in your browser. These cookies may be removed by deleting your browser cookies.

We use web beacons (single-pixel gifs) to count visitors or deliver co-branded services.

##### IV.Communications from the Site

  1. **Service Announcements & Marketing**

From time to time, it may be necessary to send out a strictly service-related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you a notification email. Users cannot opt-out of these communications though they can deactivate their account, request the Content Administrator or Subscriber remove them from the list, or remove themselves from a list. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

  2. **Promotional Offers**

TeacherWeb may send promotional offers to any email address that has been collected by the TeacherWeb system. TeacherWeb will not directly share your email address with any 3rd party organizations. Acceptance of these promotional offers is required as a Subscriber, Content Administrator, Site User, or User of the TeacherWeb service.

  3. **Tracking of Emails**

We use tagged images and personal tracking links to track emails and other correspondence. This information is used to determine undeliverable email addresses and review the success rate of our correspondence.

  4. **Newsflash**

Newsflash emails are sent by the TeacherWeb site registered user. Newsflashes are sent by the teacher. Content of Newsflashes are not regularly reviewed however this information may be used as necessary to gauge email success rates and resolve any email related issues. Additionally users may be removed from Newsflash correspondence by TeacherWeb should it be necessary for any administrative purpose that TeacherWeb decides is required.

##### V.Content Filtering 

In an effort to detect any problems with a given Teacher’s password information, TeacherWeb routinely scans all posts to the system and may remove a site or any content that it deems inappropriate. TeacherWeb may complete this activity without advance notice and makes no warranties or representations that it will review the content. TeacherWeb may remove a site based on posted content, or at its sole discretion, without providing advance notice.

##### VI.Website Access & Updates including payment

TeacherWeb collects various information whenever you access any TeacherWeb page. This information may include IP address, date and time, web browser and version information, screen resolutions, and other generally available information. Additionally when completing an update, this information may be put into special logs for later review and analysis. At time of payment additional information may be collected, stored, and analyzed for fraud purposes, for marketing research, or any other purpose that TeacherWeb deems necessary.

##### VII.Customer Service 

As necessary, TeacherWeb may communicate with you via email, phone or online to provide requested services and in regards to account-related issues. TeacherWeb may collect additional information and turn on additional logging to further track and collect information on end user behavior and activities.

##### VIII.Sharing

  1. **When Requested or Required by Law**

Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on your organization's site.

  2. **When Requested or Required by an Account Code Owner**

Any information on TeacherWeb that uses an account code (as paid by a school account or pre-service account, etc) may be turned over to the school or pre-service contact(s) as they request. Contact your school’s Primary Contact to TeacherWeb for more information regarding who has been assigned these positions and how this position-assigning process works for your organization.

  3. **Business Transitions**

In the event TeacherWeb goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, your personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. You will be notified by a prominent notice on our corporate website prior to a change of ownership or control of your personal information. For more information, see the TeacherWeb Privacy Policy Statement Changes section.

##### IX.Links

Your organization's site may contain links to other sites. TeacherWeb is not responsible for the privacy practices of other such sites. TeacherWeb privacy statement applies solely to information collected by TeacherWeb. 3rd party Content (e.g. Widgets, etc.) that is added to a site may collect additional information. TeacherWeb is not responsible for the practices of other such sites related to the information collected. 

##### X.Surveys, Support Requests, and Feedback Forms

From time to time, our site may request or gain information from you through surveys, support requests, or feedback forms. Participation in these surveys or feedback forms is voluntary. If personal information is requested, TeacherWeb will fully disclose this to you prior to submission. Information collected is used for the purposes of improving our product and services as well as marketing efforts and understanding our audience. Information received through Support Requests, including customer provided quotes may be used on the TeacherWeb site for marketing purposes.

All information collected may be used by TeacherWeb in any way it deems necessary, however it will not be disclosed to parties outside of TeacherWeb unless TeacherWeb deems it necessary, or unless it is used in TeacherWeb marketing. If used in TeacherWeb marketing, full contact information of the Subscriber will not be utilized without prior written consent.

##### XI.Security

TeacherWeb takes security seriously and employs measures to protect your information. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) have access to personally identifiable information.

Personal information is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access. If you have any questions about the security of your TeacherWeb® sites, please create a support request.

##### XII.Modifications to Personal Information

There are three ways your personal information can be modified:

  1. If your personally identifiable information changes (such as ZIP code, phone, email or postal address), or if you no longer desire full access to TeacherWeb® services, you may update or delete your personally identifiable information. This can be done by deleting your TeacherWeb® site.
  2. School account code owners have access and the ability to update personal information. These Editors only have access to their organization's user information. Your organization is responsible for compliance with any applicable regulations (e.g. COPPA).
  3. TeacherWeb may gather information from schools or pre-service personnel in your organization which would allow TeacherWeb to conduct a mass user import to update user information. For children under 13 years of age, your organization is responsible for first validating receipt of any parental consent forms. 

It is understood that any information submitted to TeacherWeb may be kept indefinitely by TeacherWeb for past and future promotional efforts, historical archiving, and on backups.

##### XIII.Privacy Policy Statement Changes

If we change our privacy policy, we will post the revised policy to <http://www.teacherweb.com/tweb/privacypolicy.aspx> and other places we deem reasonable and appropriate to keep you informed. 

When material changes affecting users under 13 years of age are made to this privacy policy, TeacherWeb will post a change notification announcement on its site. This announcement will include a link to the current privacy policy. The same notification procedure will be followed for users over the age of 13. If TeacherWeb materially changes how it uses personal information about children under age 13, the Subscriber is responsible for any required parental consent. 

##### XIV.LIMITATION OF LIABILITY

While TeacherWeb takes reasonable steps to safeguard and to prevent unauthorized access to your private information, except as may be required by law, we cannot be responsible for the acts of those who gain unauthorized access, and we make no warranty, express, implied, or otherwise, that we will prevent unauthorized access to your private information. IN NO EVENT SHALL TEACHERWEB OR ITS AFFILIATES BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES (WHETHER CONSEQUENTIAL, DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, SPECIAL OR OTHERWISE) ARISING OUT OF, OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH, A THIRD PARTY’S UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION, REGARDLESS OF WHETHER SUCH DAMAGES ARE BASED ON CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, TORT OR OTHER THEORIES OF LIABILITY, AND ALSO REGARDLESS OF WHETHER TEACHERWEB WAS GIVEN ACTUAL OR CONSTRUCTIVE NOTICE THAT DAMAGES WERE POSSIBLE. 

This Privacy Policy is not intended to be a contract and or to create any legal rights on the part of Users or Subscribers. Instead, it is intended to serve as a description of the efforts TeacherWeb takes to prevent unauthorized access, sound management of authorized users, and protection of computer system content and transaction integrity. For more information about our policies for protecting your personal information, see our Security Policy (http://teacherweb.com/tweb/privacypolicy.aspx).

This Privacy Policy is subject to TeacherWeb’s Terms and Conditions (<http://teacherweb.com/tweb/terms.aspx> ). In the event of any conflict between this Privacy Policy and TeacherWeb’s Terms and Conditions, TeacherWeb’s Terms and Conditions shall govern.

##### XIV.Contact Information

At TeacherWeb, we take privacy issues very seriously. If you have any questions, suggestions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please contact us. 

TeacherWeb, Inc.  
ATTN: Privacy Questions  
PO Box 1099  
Ridgefield, CT 06877  
URL: http://www.teacherweb.com/tweb/privacypolicy.aspx

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact TeacherWeb.
